嘿
Hey.
我知道你很害怕 我也知道你很生气
I know you're scared, and I know you're angry,
但我向你保证 我们是来帮助你的
but I promise you, we are here to help you.
嘿 德瑞克
Hey, Derek, Derek.
如果你继续这么做 只会把自己弄伤
If you keep doing that, you're gonna hurt yourself.
冷静下来 我们聊聊 好吗？
Just calm down so we can talk, okay?
你知道我是谁吗？
Do you know who I am?
一个邪恶的儿童绑架犯
An evil child kidnapper.
好吧 我明白你为什么会这么想
Okay, I understand why you would think that,
但我并不邪恶
but I'm not evil.
我只是个妈妈 一个普通的妈妈
I'm just a mom, a regular mom.
那是我的儿子 威尔
That's my son, Will.
僵尸男孩
Zombie boy.
你知道他们为什么这么叫他吗？
You know why they call him that?
因为他死而复生了
Because he died and came back to life.
但人们不知道的是 他失踪的时候
But what people don't know is that when he went missing,
是被一个吓人的可怕怪物掳走的
he was taken by a terrible, scary monster.
而现在 那个可怕的怪物要来抓你了
And now, that scary monster is after you.
对 我知道 啥先生告诉我了 所以你得放我走
Yeah, I know. Mr. Whatsit told me, which is why you need to let me go.
不 啥先生 不是他自称的那个人 好吗？
No, no. Mr. Whatsit is not who he says he is, okay?
他在骗你 所有这些怪物 都是为他工作的
He is lying to you. All these monsters, they work for him.
所以我们把你带到这个谷仓来 我们本以为这个谷仓很安全
That's why we took you here to this barn. We thought this barn was safe,
但他找到我们了
but he's found us.
所以我们必须 再次把你转移到他找不到的地方
So we have to move you again, somewhere he can't find you.
所以如果我解开绳子 你会配合 和我们一起走吗？
So if I untie you, will you cooperate and come with us?
拜托了？
Please?
好 太好了
Okay, great.
你是个非常勇敢的孩子 德瑞克 我想让你知道这一点
You're a very brave kid, Derek. I want you to know that.
非常…
Very--
-妈妈！ -胡扯！
MOM Shit
-放开我！别碰我！ -德瑞克 拜托！
-Let me go! Get off of me! -Derek. Please!
-门！去关上门！ -救命！
-The door! Get the door! -Help me!
放开我！
Let me go! Get off me!
-别乱动！ -离我远点！
-Stay down! -Get away!
谁来救救我！我被绑架了！
Somebody help! I'm being kidnapped!
离我远点！放开我！
Get away from me! Let me go!
妈 绳子！我需要绳子！
Mom, the rope! I need the rope!
放开我！吃土吧！
-Let me go! Eat dirt! -Ah!
有种就过来试试 蠢蛋！
Come try us, dipshit!
该死！
Shit!
伙计！她没有骗你 好吗？
Dude! She's not lying to you, okay?
啥先生是个大坏蛋 是他派那些怪物来抓你的
Mr. Whatsit is a very bad guy. He sent the monsters after you.
你给我有多远滚多远！
Suck my fat one!
天啊！什么？
Jesus! What?
你刚刚给自己判了死刑 蠢蛋！
You just signed your death warrant, dipshit!
你就是个神经病 你会进监狱的！
You're a psycho, and you're going to jail!
-怪物就要来了！ -我们是想要帮助你
-There is a monster coming! -We're trying to help you.
-啦啦啦 -德瑞克 拜托！
-La, la, la, la. -Derek, please!
你必须要下来
You gotta come down.
我没在听 啦啦啦
I'm not listening. La, la, la, la.
退后！
Stay back!
你想要他 就得先过我这一关！
You want him, you're gonna have to come through me!
耶 我们撞上了！我们撞上他了！
Yeah, we got him! We got him!
它进入颠倒世界了 又冲着我们来了！
It flipped! It's headed back towards us!
拜托 你在干什么？我们得掉头！
Come on. What are you doing, man? We gotta turn around!
等一下 大门就像花生酱脆球 对吧？
Wait. Gates are like Peanut Butter Boppers, right?
-什么？ -外面又脆又硬
-What? -The outside is, like, crunchy and tough.
但咬下去 里面就是软糯又顺滑的内馅
But bite down on it, it gives way to a gooey, creamy core.
朋友 你到底在说什么啊？
Dude, what the hell are you talking about?
只要开得够快 我觉得宝马车能在门上撞开一个口子
I drive fast enough, the beamer can punch a hole into the gate,
然后我们就可以在魔王的主场 在颠倒世界里追踪它了
and then we can track the Demo on its home turf in the Upside Down.
-跟着它直接回家 -我们要失去信号了！
-Follow it back home. -We're losing the signal!
如果撞车 我们就什么都追踪不了了
We won't be able to follow anything if we crash!
如果它像脆球一样 我们就不会撞
We won't crash if it's like a Bopper!
快要跟丢了！
It's almost gone!
上吧
Do it.
-天啊！ -天啊
-Oh my God! Oh my God! -Jesus.
-天啊！ -我没问题 没问题的！
-Oh my God! Oh my God! -I got it! I got it!
天啊 不！
Oh God, no!
-不会成功的 -我们不会成功的！
-It's not gonna work. -We're not gonna make it!
-不是脆球 停下！ -慢点啊！老天爷！
-It's not a Bopper. Stop! -Slow down! Jesus Christ!
-该死！天啊！ -抓紧了！
-Shit! Oh my God! -Hang on!
成功了！
We did it! Woo!
信号？
Signal?
-很强！ -天啊！
-Strong! -Oh my God!
我们抓住你了 混蛋！ 我们抓住你了！
We got you, son of a bitch! We got you!
威尔！
Will!? Will!
我就在这里 威尔
I'm right here, Will.
没事的
It's okay.
有我在 有我在呢
I got you. I got you.
有我在 亲爱的
I got you, sweetie.
《怪奇物语》5
第四集：魔法师
嗯 叮铃咣当？
Uh, hockety-pockety?
对了 没错
Oh, yes, yes, that's right.
叮铃咣当唰啦啦 零零碎碎都装下
Hockety-pockety wockety wack Odds and ends and bric-a-brac
-我马上就来 孩子 -什么？
-I'll be with you in just a minute, son. -What?
行李马上就收好了！
Packing's almost done!
嘘！
Shush!
果冻！
Jelly!
艾伦·米勒？
Alan Miller?
不好意思 这是怎么回事？
I'm sorry, what is this about?
是你的女儿 先生
It's your daughter, sir.
（军事警察）
（罗恩山公墓）
看起来这小子 要带我们抄近路 穿过罗恩公墓
Our boy's taking us on a shortcut through Roane Cemetery.
-那都快到县边界线了 -这玩意不会累的吗？
-That's almost at the county line. -Doesn't this thing get tired?
很不幸 事实恰恰相反 我觉得他在加速
Unfortunately, it looks like the opposite. I think he's speeding up.
-什么？ -我快要失去信号了
-What? -I'm losing the signal.
你一定是在耍我吧！
You've gotta be shitting me!
-你还能开快点吗？ -让我试试
-Can you go faster? -Let's see.
亨德森 你得跟我说话 有什么发现？
Henderson, you've gotta talk to me. What do you got?
-亨德森 什么… -我接收到了干扰信号
-Henderson, what-- -I'm picking up interference.
-这很重要吗？ -这意味着我听不到信号了
-How is that important? -It means I can't hear the signal.
-那就再用点力听 -什么意思？
-Listen harder. -What do you mean?
-你想戴上试试吗？ -我在开车！
-You wanna put these on? -I'm driving!
你负责开车 我负责导航
You do the driving. I do the navigating.
-那是什么？ -你才是问题所在
-What is that? -I don't know.
史蒂夫 放慢车速
Steve, slow down.
他到底在不在我们前面？
Is he ahead of us or not?
-史蒂夫！ -史蒂夫 小心！
-Steve! -Steve, watch out!
-史蒂夫 小心！ -该死！
-Steve, watch out! -Shit!
乔纳森 我是妈妈 请回答我 完毕
Jonathan, it's Mom. Answer me, please. Over.
乔纳森 请回答我
Jonathan, please answer.
乔纳森、南茜、达斯汀 我是乔伊斯 请回答我
Jonathan, Nancy, Dustin, it's Joyce. Please answer me.
嘿
Hey.
有进展吗？
Any luck?
从好的方面来说 我想这意味着他们成功进去了
Well, on the plus side, I guess that means they made it through.
你想看看他们要去哪里吗？
Do you wanna see where they're headed?
这是什么？
What is it?
我不知道
I don't know,
但我能感觉到这对他来说很重要
but I could feel it's important to him.
对啥先生很重要？
To Mr… Whatsit?
他的真名是亨利
His real name is Henry.
也就是维克那
AKA Vecna.
也就是一号
AKA One.
名字也太多了
That's too many names.
你不如闭上嘴好好听着吧 蠢蛋
Why won't you just zip it and listen, dipshit?
我有一种感觉 他不想让我去那里
I had this feeling he didn't want me there.
我不该看到这个的
I wasn't supposed to see it.
你以前从未这么接近过集体意识
You've never been this close to the hive mind before.
我的意思是 那东西距离你只有几十公分
I mean, that thing was, like, feet away.
在躁点电台 有时候信号太强
Sometimes at The Squawk, when a signal comes in too strong,
就会让整个系统过载
it overloads the whole system.
我想这次就是这样 过载了
I think that's what this was, an overload.
你不只是接入了集体意识
You didn't just tap into the hive mind.
你直接入侵了该死的控制中心
You jacked right in to the goddamn control center.
那霍莉呢 霍莉在哪里？
And Holly. Where was Holly?
霍莉 她…
Holly. Holly, she was…
她被固定在这个尖顶上
She was attached to this… this spire.
出于一些原因 她成为了它的一部分 就好像这个尖顶对她做了些什么
And she became a part of it somehow, like it was doing something to her.
还有其他人
And… And there were others.
还有另外三个人
There were three others.
我以为维克那只是冲着蠢蛋来的
I thought Vecna was just coming for dipshit.
我也这么以为 但我知道德瑞克 是因为他正好从我身边走过
So did I. But I only knew about Derek because he walked right past me.
恰逢其时了
Serendipitous timing.
-你听到了吗？恰逢其时 -我不懂这是什么意思
-You hear that? Serendipitous. -I don't know what that means.
我真的不喜欢所有这些额外的尖顶
I'm really not loving all of these extra spires.
第一天晚上 维克那绑架了霍莉 第二天晚上 他又掳走了三个人
I mean, night one, Vecna kidnaps Holly. Night two, he takes three more.
他在升级 他还会掳走更多人
He's escalating. And he's coming for more.
再加八个人 如果这图准确的话 也就是说总人数达到了12
Eight more, if this is accurate, which brings him to a total of 12.
他要拿他们做什么？为什么是孩子？
What does he want with them? And why kids?
-为什么12个？ -不知道
-And why 12? -I don't know.
但我们必须 在他掳走更多人之前阻止他
But we have to stop him before he takes any more
为达斯汀和其他人争取时间 找到这个地方 找到霍莉
and buy Dustin and the others time to find this place, to find Holly.
如果我们能准确定位他的目标 我们也许可以把他们救出霍金斯
If we can pinpoint his exact targets, we could get them out of Hawkins.
远离维克那的控制范围
And out of Vecna's reach.
你忘了我们被隔离了吗？
Did you forget we're quarantined?
-还不止这一点 -还有一个问题
-That's not all. -There's another problem.
在过来的路上 我们看到士兵们将黛比·米勒
On the way here, we saw soldiers load Debbie Miller
送上一辆公交车 车上还有其他孩子
onto a bus with a bunch more kids.
我们跟着他们又走了两个街区 他们把更多的孩子送上了这辆车
We followed them for two blocks more, and they loaded more kids onto it.
我觉得他们并不是要送他们去学校
I don't think they were taking them to school.
想要这些孩子的不止是维克那一个人
Vecna's not the only one that wants these kids.
霍莉被掳走的那天晚上 十一就在惠勒家
Eleven was at the Wheeler house the same night Holly was taken.
24小时后 又多了三个失踪的孩子
Twenty-four hours later, we've got three more missing kids.
霍金斯一共有73个九到十岁的孩子
There's 73 children in Hawkins between the age of nine and ten.
如果模式成立 我们的下一个目标就在这群人中
If the pattern holds, our next target will be from this group.
你认为是十一掳走了这些孩子？
And you believe Eleven has taken these kids?
目的是什么？
For what purpose?
杀死他们 保护他们 原因并不重要
Killing them, protecting them. The reason doesn't matter.
这些孩子呢？他们现在在哪里？
These children? Where are they now?
随时会抵达军管区 我需要你去那里
Arriving at the MAC-Z any moment, which is where I want you.
我应该去找艾克斯中尉 找到艾克斯 我就能找到…
I should be looking for Lt. Akers. I find Akers, I find--
你会找到一个死人
You'll find a dead man.
去军管区报告 上校 这是命令
Report to the MAC-Z, Colonel. That's an order.
少将
Major General.
恕我直言
With all due respect,
这些孩子有生命危险
these kids are in danger.
把他们当作诱饵似乎有点…
To use them as bait seems…
似乎有点什么？中士？
Seems what, Sergeant?
鲁莽
Reckless.
只有你无法保护他们 这才会是鲁莽之举
It's only reckless if you fail to protect them.
你是在告诉我 你无法保护他们吗 中士？
Are you telling me you can't protect them, Sergeant?
不 长官
No, ma'am.
很好
Good.
抱歉吓到你了
I'm sorry for scaring you.
我已经很久没见到任何人了 所以…
I haven't seen anyone in… a really long time, so…
我猜我是太兴奋了
I guess I got excited.
好消息是看起来没那么深
Good news is it doesn't look that deep.
还不需要缝针
Not enough for stitches.
但肯定挺刺痛的 对吧？
I bet it stings though, huh?
你可以和我说话的 你知道吧
You can talk to me, you know.
不用怕我
I won't bite.
你还记得我吧？
You do remember me, right?
我去过你家
I've been to your house.
去过很多次
Like, a lot.
你是麦克斯 麦克斯·梅菲尔德
You're Max, Max Mayfield.
你玩滑板 从不摘下你的随身听
You skateboard and never take off your Walkman.
就是我
-That's me. -But--
-但是… -我为什么会在这里
-But How am I in here
我明明在霍金斯总医院昏迷着？
when I'm in a coma in Hawkins General?
这是个非常合理的问题
That's a very reasonable question.
我们该走了 这里不安全 来吧
We should get going. It's not safe here. Come on.
我们要去哪里？
Where are we going?
我家
My home.
好吧 我不能走太远 我是来见亨利的
Well, I can't go far. I came here to meet Henry.
-你认识亨利吗？ -可以这么说吧
-Do you know Henry? -You could say that.
他给我留了这张纸条 看到了吗？ 他叫我在画了X的地方和他碰头
He left me this note. See? And he told me to meet him right here at the X.
我觉得他是招惹了怪物们
I think he's in trouble with the monsters.
亨利会做很多事 但招惹怪物并不是其中之一
Henry is a lot of things, but in trouble with the monsters is not one of them.
-但纸条上写着… -我知道纸条上写了什么
-But the note says-- -I know what the note says.
你怎么知道他没惹上麻烦？ 他还叫我快点！
How do you know he's not in trouble? He said hurry!
霍莉 我知道纸条上写了什么 因为那不是亨利写的 是我写的
Holly, I know what the note says because Henry didn't write it. I did.
我不…我不明白
I don't… I don't understand.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不想说谎 我只是… 我得确保你会来这里
I didn't want to lie. I… I just… I had to make sure that you came here.
你也是他们中的一员 对吧？
You're one of them, aren't you?
-什么的一员？ -怪物们
-One of what? -The monsters.
-我看起来像怪物吗？ -我不知道 也许你伪装过了
-Do I look like a monster? -I don't know. Maybe you're in disguise.
你的穿着很奇怪 而且你明明处在昏迷中
You're dressed weird, and you're in a coma.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 怪物会知道 你哥哥本来想搞个莫霍克发型
Well, would a monster know that your brother tried to get a mohawk
直到你姐姐阻止了他
until your sister stopped him,
让他逃过了霍金斯高中高一新生
saving him from possibly the greatest social humiliation
史上最尴尬的社死现场吗？
that a freshman has ever experienced at Hawkins High?
他这个莫霍克发型是什么颜色？
What color was this mohawk?
辣橙色
Hot orange.
我个人认为 用“热辣”这个形容词有点讽刺 但是…
And personally, I think the use of the word "hot" is a bit ironic, but…
大家都说我太消极了
People say I'm too negative.
我只是觉得我很诚实
I just think I'm honest.
来吧
Come on.
欢迎
Welcome.
嘿
Hey.
甚至还自带风景
It even comes with a view.
我们在哪里？
Where are we?
在一段记忆里
In a memory.
它存在于一个 有一千个记忆的世界里
Which exists inside a world of 1,000 memories.
我知道看着可能挺不错
I know it might look nice,
但并非如此
but it's not.
这个地方 这个世界…
This place, this world…
是一座监狱
It's a prison.
亨利的监狱
Henry's prison.
没事的 亲爱的
It's okay, sweetie.
这些都是好人 他们会确保所有人的安全
These are the good guys. They're going to keep everyone safe.
就把这想成是一次校外参观吧
Just try and think of this as a field trip.
嗯哼？一次学习探险
Mm-hmm. A learning expedition.
（禁区）
货物已抵达 我再说一遍 货物已抵达
Cargo has arrived. I repeat, cargo has arrived.
他们被带进了 从图书馆数起第二个军营
They're taking them into a barracks second from the library.
隧道
Tunnels.
对 看到了吗？军管区的北部隧道 刚好就在这些军营下面
Yeah. See? The north tunnel of the MAC-Z runs right underneath the barracks.
-交好运了 -总有一天得交点好运吧
-Lucky break. -Bound to happen one of these days.
想让这计划成功 就需要更多运气
Gonna need more luck if we want this plan to work.
如果我们没猜错的话 军方想要保护这些孩子
If we're right, the military is trying to protect these kids.
所以这个军营会有重兵把守
So this barracks is gonna be heavily guarded.
我们得暗中 从隧道里向上挖 挖到军营里
We have to dig up into the barracks, unnoticed,
把孩子们抓出来 交给穆雷 偷偷运出霍金斯
grab the kids, get them to Murray, smuggle them out of Hawkins.
还得在任何人注意到他们消失之前
All before anyone notices they're gone.
-迪克 -什么？
-Dick. -What?
什么？
What? Oh.
对不起 我刚刚是说出来了吗？ 我以为我只是在自己脑子里说
Sorry. Did I say that out loud? I thought I was talking in my head.
但你们知道 汤姆、迪克和哈利 对吧？
But you guys know Tom, Dick, and Harry, right?
真的吗？你们都没看过《大逃亡》？
Seriously? None of you have seen The Great Escape?
好吧 基本上是讲这些战俘的 好吗？
Basically, it's about these POWs, right?
他们被困在了就像这样的军营里
And they're stuck in a barracks just like this one.
他们需要逃跑 于是他们挖了些隧道
They need to escape, so they dig these tunnels,
管这些隧道叫做汤姆、迪克和哈利
and they call their tunnels Tom, Dick, and Harry.
他们必须 把隧道藏起来 不被纳粹发现
They have to hide the tunnels from the Nazis.
于是把汤姆藏在阴暗角落里 把哈利藏在炉子下面
So they put Tom in this dark corner, and they put Harry under the stove,
把迪克藏在洗手间 就我个人而言 对我们的任务来说 我喜欢迪克
and they put Dick in the washroom. And personally, for us, I like Dick.
对不起 洗手间 其实我甚至都不喜欢…算了
Oh, um… Sorry. The washroom. I actually don't even… Never mind.
好吧 假设我们选迪克
Okay, say we go with Dick.
我们要怎么找到洗手间？
How do we find the washroom?
我们要怎么让孩子们去那里？
And how do we get the kids to it?
我们怎么知道 维克那盯上了哪些孩子？
How do we know which kids are being targeted by Vecna?
我们利用内应 这个人要能进入军营
We use an inside man, someone who could get into the barracks,
测量到洗手间的距离 找出哪些孩子见过了啥先生
measure the distance to the washroom, find out which kids have seen Mr. Whatsit,
并以某种方式避开军方
and somehow avoid the military.
这计划是不错 但是不是有那么点…
Well, that's a lovely plan, but isn't it a tad…
《碟中谍》的感觉了
Mission Impossible-y.
对啊 我的意思是 迈克 你要找谁来做这件事？
Yeah. I mean, Mike, who are you gonna get to do this?
邦德？夏威夷神探？
Bond? Magnum?
不 我们想要的不是超级间谍
No, no, we don't want a superspy.
我们想要的恰恰相反 我们想要不会被怀疑的人
We want the opposite. We want someone no one would suspect.
一个可以来去自如 没人会问问题的人
Someone that could just walk in, no questions asked.
唯一一个军方没能抓走的孩子
The one kid the military failed to wrangle.
什么？
What?
西大门塔楼有两个步兵
Two grunts in the tower by the west gate.
东大门旁边的塔楼里还有一个
One more in the tower by the east gate.
地面上有一、二、三、四个
One, two, three, four on the ground.
我真希望你是对的 维克那就在里面
I hope to God you're right, and Vecna is in there,
因为我们可能会在试图闯入时就丧命
because we might just die trying to break in.
我是对的
I am right.
你不可能在所有事上都是对的 你的理论前后并不一致
You can't be right about everything. Your theories aren't exactly lining up.
-为什么？ -你听到了氪石的声音
-Why not? -You heard kryptonite.
说明维克那如果在里面 他无法使用超能力
If Vecna's in there, he doesn't have his powers.
如果他无法使用超能力
If he doesn't have his powers,
他怎么可能参与了霍莉被绑架的事？
how could he have anything to do with Holly's kidnapping?
你可以在我杀死他之前问一问他
You can ask him before I kill him.
那个围栏有多高？
How high is that fence?
嘿 你不能去跳越那个围栏
Hey, you're not jumping that.
为什么不能？
Why not?
因为这不是训练 这是现实世界的情况
Because this is not training. This is a real-world situation.
屋顶是金属的
And that roof is metal.
如果跳的时候撞到 就会惊动整个该死的基地
You hit that on a jump, you're gonna alert the whole damn base.
如果我配合雷声的时间就不会
Not if I time it with the thunder.
是啊
Yeah.
七秒
It's seven seconds.
一、二、三、四、五、六…
One, two, three, four, five, six…
七
Seven.
行吧 你运气好
Okay. You got lucky.
霍珀 能听到吗？
-Hopper, do you copy? -Dustin!
-达斯汀！ -完毕 我是达斯汀
Over. This is Dustin.
霍珀 能听到吗？我是达斯汀
Hopper, do you copy? This is Dustin.
嘿 我是霍珀 我听到了
Hey, hey, it's Hop. I copy.
该死！好的 他们还活着！
Holy shit! Okay. They're alive!
艾尔 问问艾尔的情况
El! Ask about El.
艾尔跟你在一起吗？完毕
El. Is El with you? Over.
对 我在 完毕
Yes. I'm here. Over.
好 耶 太棒了
Okay. Yay. Terrific.
我不知道 有没有打扰你们做重要的事 但是…
I don't know if you're caught up in something important, but--
-达斯汀！ -跟我们碰头！
-Dustin. Come on. -Meet us!
请来罗恩公墓教堂跟我们碰头
Meet us at Roane Cemetery church, please.
罗恩公墓 你们怎么会从那里联系我们？
Roane Cemetery. How the hell are you contacting us from there?
对 你们还不知道 我们在颠倒世界里
Right. You don't know. We're in the Upside Down.
什么？
What?
长话短说 我们是在 用我们的遥测追踪器追踪一个魔王
Long story short, we're here to track a Demogorgon using our telemetry tracker,
然后撞到了墙上 真的墙 史蒂夫的宝马卡住了
only to then hit a wall. Literally. Now, Steve's beamer is stuck,
所以我们需要艾尔 用超能力把车弄下来
so we need El to come and pry it loose using her powers
这样我们就能继续搜索这个魔王
so we can resume the search for said Demogorgon
理论上就能带我们找到霍莉 我这么说你们能听明白吗？
which will, in theory, lead us to Holly. Does any of this make sense?
需要更多细节吗？ 有问题吗？有什么担忧吗？完毕
Do you need additional details? Questions? Concerns? Over.
你们撞到了墙上？
You hit a wall?
具体是什么样的墙？
What kind of wall, exactly?
有点…难以形容
Uh… it's a bit… hard to describe.
-有点… -很大吗？
-Sort of… -Huge?
恶心
Disgusting.
闻起来像亨德森的腋窝
Smells like Henderson's armpit.
我们也撞到了同样的东西 但不是在罗恩公墓
We hit the same thing, but not at the Roane Cemetery.
我们这个是在 老哈根桥东南方向400米左右
We hit it a quarter mile southeast of the old Hagen Bridge.
那是镇子的另一边
That's the opposite side of town.
真有意思
Fascinating.
我们不知道那是什么 但我们认为霍莉在墙后面
We don't know what it is, but we think Holly's behind it.
不用尝试冲破了 你们过不去的
Don't bother trying to break through. You can't.
我们正在想解决办法
We're working on a solution.
-南茜 -解决办法？什么样的办法？
-Nancy. -Solution? What kind of solution?
等等 什么样的解决办法？霍珀！
Wait, what kind of solution? Hopper!
听着 我们需要 保持无线电频道畅通 好吗？
Listen, we gotta keep the airwaves clear, all right?
我们会来找你们的 待在那里别动
We'll come get you. Just stay put.
你觉得他们安全吗？
You think they're safe?
跟我们比起来？是的
I mean, compared to us? Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
让我们看看训练有没有效果吧
Let's go see if that training has paid off.
你允许我跳了？
You're gonna let me jump?
走吧 不然我就要改变主意了
Let's go before I change my mind.
维克那的诅咒
Vecna's curse,
永远都不会消失
it never goes away.
永远都不会离开你
Never leaves you.
他每抓走一个受害者
With each victim that he took,
就会创造一扇新的大门
he created a new gate.
通往颠倒世界的大门？
A gate to the Upside Down?
他把我抓走时 打开了第四扇 也是最后一扇大门
When he took me, he opened the fourth, final gate,
将霍金斯一分为二
splitting Hawkins in two.
等等 但是如果啥先生… 我是说亨利把你抓走了
Wait, but if Mr. Whatsit… I mean Henry, took you,
你怎么会在这里？
how are you here?
你的意思是 我为什么没死？
You mean, shouldn't I be dead?
没事 这个问题合情合理
It's okay. It's a fair question.
我绝对应该是死了
I definitely should be.
而且 有那么一瞬间…
And for a moment…
我的确死了
I was.
我不知道我离开了多久
I don't know how long I was gone.
但之后 我感觉到有东西在呼唤着我
But then I felt something… calling to me.
♪ Life could be dream ♪
♪ If I could take you up In Paradise up above ♪
♪ If you would tell me I'm the only… ♪
只演一晚 不要错过 门票只要50美分
One night only. Don't miss it. Tickets are only 50 cents.
换成你们书呆子的语言 就是两个25美分硬币
That's two quarters for you poindexters.
-乔伊斯！这就是你那个愚蠢的剧？ -你最好是去 哈林顿！
-Joyce! This that stupid play of yours? -I better see you there, Harrington.
周五晚上？想得美
Friday night? You wish.
♪ Life could be dream ♪
好球 混蛋
Nice shot, jerk.
♪ If only all my precious plans Would come true ♪
不知为何 我出现在了另一个时间
Somehow, I was in another time.
霍金斯
Hawkins.
30年前
Thirty years ago.
时间旅行
Time travel.
只不过我本人并不在现场
Only, I wasn't actually there.
不是真的在场 我只是…
Not really. I was just…
观察者的身份？
an observer.
（主演：小霍珀、凯伦）
（首次出演：亨利·克里尔）
我就是在那时明白了
And that's when I understood.
我被困在了 亨利的大脑里 他的记忆里
I was trapped inside Henry's mind, his memories.
就像是被邪恶的变态混蛋统治的
Like a nightmare prison world
一个噩梦般的监狱世界
ruled by an evil, psychopathic piece of shit.
就像坎马卓兹
Like Camazotz.
坎马…什么？
Cama… What?
坎马卓兹 《时间的皱折》里的
Camazotz. From A Wrinkle in Time.
-从没读过 -读一读吧 很精彩
-Never read it. -You should. It's amazing.
坎马卓兹是在它控制下的黑暗星球
Camazotz is like this dark planet that's under the control of IT,
它是一个没有肉体的邪恶巨型大脑
which is this giant, disembodied, evil brain.
总之 梅格的爸爸… 梅格是书中的主角
Anyways, Meg's dad… Meg's the main character.
.…他被囚禁在了那里
…he gets taken prisoner there
所以亨利有点像它 你就有点像梅格的爸爸
So, Henry's kinda like IT, and you're kinda like Meg's dad.
好吧 那…
Okay. Well…
我不知道梅格的爸爸 会不会同意 但在我看来
I don't know if Meg's dad would agree, but the way I see it,
当你被囚禁在 一个混乱的监狱世界里时
when you're a prisoner in a messed up prison world,
就真的只有几扇门可以选
you really only have a few doors open to you.
一号门 自尽
Door one, you take your own life.
二号门 认命
Door two, accept your fate.
-要么就是三号门… -逃跑
-Or door three… -You escape.
-我选了三号门 -这似乎是最好的一扇门
-I chose door three. -That seems like the best door.
于是我就一直在移动
So, I kept moving.
从一段记忆移动到另一段记忆
From memory to memory.
但是这地方是个迷宫
Only, this place is a maze.
我迷了路 晕头转向 晕头转向到
I became lost, turned around. I got so turned around,
又回到了最开始的地方
I actually ended up right back at the beginning.
我就是在那时听到了她的声音
And that's when I heard her.
我听到凯特·布什的声音
I heard Kate Bush.
她是你的朋友吗？
Is she one of your friends?
可以这么说吧
You could say that.
♪ Do you wanna hear About the deal that I'm making? ♪
音乐总能有办法找到你 即使是在最黑暗的地方
Music has a way of finding you, even in the darkest of places.
卢卡斯之前用它找到了我 引导我从维克那的大脑中跑出来
Lucas had used it before, to reach me, to guide me out of Vecna's mind,
回到了光明世界
back to the light.
♪ If I only could make a deal with God ♪
♪ And I'd get him to swap our places ♪
♪ Be runnin' up that road ♪
所以这个音乐 是卢卡斯在现实世界给你播放的？
So, this music was coming from Lucas, from the real world?
即使过去了这么久
Even after all this time,
他依然没有放弃我
he hadn't given up on me.
如果你跟着这个音乐走
If you follow this music,
然后呢？
then what?
然后 它就会带我离开这里
Then it would lead me out of here.
回家
Back home.
至少我之前是这么以为的
At least, that's what I thought.
但后来…
But then…
一切都出错了
everything went wrong.
♪ Oh, come on, angel Come on, come on, darlin' ♪
♪ Let's exchange the… ♪
嘿！
Hey!
你到底在干什么？ 你不识字吗 孩子？严禁擅自闯入
What the hell are you doing? Can't you read, kid? No trespassing.
对 我看到了 警官
Right, I see that, officer.
只是…我学校的人都不见了
It's just… my school is missing.
（禁区）
走吧
Let's go.
快走
Move it.
我的妈呀！那是激光炮吗？
Holy shit! Are those laser blasters?
有可能哦
Might just be.
如果你不快点走 可能就会把你给炸死
And they'll blast you if you don't keep it moving.
-孩子们 -抓不到我！
-Boys. -Can't get me!
孩子们！
Boys!
好了 绝对不可以
All right. Absolutely not.
哇
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
这位是查普曼二等兵 他怎么说你就怎么做
This is Private Chapman. You do exactly as he says.
你有任何问题 就来问他
You got any questions, direct them to him.
我该去哪里解手？
Where might I relieve myself?
破门杆
Breaking bar.
铲子
Shovel.
五副护目镜
Five safety goggles.
一个测距轮 还有…
A surveyor's wheel and…
先别急着鼓掌
Hold for applause.
圣诞老人的雪橇 已经准备好迎接他的驯鹿了
Santa's sleigh is ready for his reindeer.
我们有固定的长椅 安全带、泡沫垫
We got built-in benches, seat belts, foam padding.
被绑架的孩子所需要的应有尽有
Everything a kidnapped child could desire.
泡沫垫？
Foam padding?
我们可不想要 任何货物在运输过程中碰伤 对吧？
Don't want to break any eggs en route, now do we?
我进来了 能听到吗？ 重复 我进来了 能听到吗？
I'm in. Do you copy? Repeat, I'm in. Do you copy?
是的 对 我们能听到 你在哪里？
Yes, yes, we copy. We copy. Where are you?
厕所 最后一个隔间 从正门进来我用了45步
Bathroom. Back stall. 45 of my paces from the front entrance.
好样的 现在 去把所有见过啥先生的人都找来
Good job. Now round up anyone who's seen Mr. Whatsit,
我们很快就到
and we'll be there soon.
记住了 你不是蠢蛋德瑞克 你是…
And remember, you're not Dipshit Derek. You're--
讨人喜欢的德瑞克
Delightful Derek.
（故障）
好吧 等你把门打开 我进去之后…
Okay, once you get that gate open, and I'm inside…
-就由你领头 -没错
-You lead. -That's right.
那你呢？
And you?
我会毁掉你的氪石 别担心
I will destroy your kryptonite. Don't worry.
好
Okay.
好了 加油吧 拜托了 你没问题的 你能行的
All right, come on. Come on, you got this. You got this.
等一下 你出手太早了
Wait. You're too early. You're too early.
老天啊
God.
对不起
Sorry.
你想害得你老爸心脏病发作吗？
You trying to give your old man a heart attack?
顺便说一句 干得好
Nice job, by the way.
霍珀？
Hop?
什么事？
Yeah?
谢谢
Thank you.
谢我什么？
For what?
谢谢你教我
For teaching me.
谢谢你信任我
And trusting me.
永远如此
Always.
报应之日已经来临
The day of reckoning has arrived.
考虑到这一点 啥先生派我来
With this in mind, I've been sent by Mr. Whatsit
召集被选中之人
to gather the chosen ones.
如果啥先生拜访过你 现在就告诉我
If you've been visited by Mr. Whatsit, speak now.
等到夜幕降临时 跟着我去厕所
And when night falls, follow me to the latrine,
我会带领你们 去见我们的救世主 去安全的地方
and I will lead you to our savior, to safety.
德瑞克疯了
Derek's gone mental.
怪物就要来了 你们都会死的
The monsters are coming, and you're all gonna die.
德瑞克？
Derek?
你刚刚说的是亨利吗？
Were you talking about Henry?
德瑞克有消息了吗？
Any word from Derek yet?
还没有
Not yet.
再给他些时间吧 还没过多久
Just give him time. It hasn't been that long.
我只是无法释怀
I just can't get over the fact
全世界的命运 寄托在该死的德瑞克·特恩鲍身上
that the fate of the world rests on Derek freakin' Turnbow.
当你照镜子的时候 镜子里的你是海豹突击队员吗？
When you look in the mirror, do you see a Navy SEAL looking back at you?
有时候人们需要有人相信他们
Sometimes people need someone to believe in them.
然后他们就能做出惊人的事情
And then they can do amazing things.
你妈妈和罗宾似乎相处得更好了
Your mom and Robin are getting along better.
毕竟妈妈吓跑了那个魔王
Well, it didn't hurt that Mom scared off that Demo.
救了罗宾一命 救了所有人
Saved Robin's life, everybody's life.
所以当你妈妈拿着斧头的时候
So, when your mom, when she had her axe,
你能看到她？ 通过魔王的眼睛看到她那种？
you could see her? -Like, through the Demo's eyes? -Yeah.
对 我离集体意识特别近
And I was so close to the hive,
就好像我 能感觉到它的感受 它的那种愤怒
it's like I could feel what it was feeling, like this anger.
但我自己也还在里面
That I was still in there too.
我很害怕 很担心我妈妈
And I was afraid. I was afraid for my mom.
-你想要保护她 -对 但我做不到
-You wanted to protect her. -Yeah. But I… I just couldn't.
就像是在看一部关不掉的恐怖电影
It was like this scary movie you just can't turn off.
芝麻开门
Open sesame.
好吧 玩得开心
Oh. Well, have fun.
谢谢
Thanks.
-你确定你没有吗？ -没有什么？
-Are you positive you didn't? -Didn't what?
把恐怖电影关掉
Turn off the scary movie.
保护你妈妈 而不是反过来
Protect your mom, not the other way around.
无意冒犯 我知道她很厉害 但你懂的
No offense. I know she's badass and everything, but you know.
-是的 她身高1米6 -对！
-Yeah, she's 5'3". -Yeah!
而维克那喜欢 像木偶大师那样控制集体意识
And Vecna likes to control the hive mind like a puppet master.
所以也许你接入集体意识时 同样也可以施展控制
So maybe when you tap into the hive, you can pull the strings too.
只不过我不是维克那
Except I'm not Vecna.
你其实算是吧
You sorta are.
你是想说我很邪恶 一心想着要毁灭世界？
You're trying to say that I'm evil and hell-bent on destroying the world?
绝对的
Totally.
不 我只是想说 你懂的 你像他一样是个巫师
No, I'm just saying that, you know, you're like a wizard like him.
在龙与地下城里 迈克 现实中可不是
In D&D, Mike, not real life.
没错 现实生活中 你更像是个魔法师
True. In real life, you're more like a sorcerer,
因为你的超能力 不是从咒语书里来的 而是天生的
because your powers don't come from a book of spells. They're innate.
听着 就疯狂的理论而言 我曾有过更疯狂的理论
Listen, as far as crazy theories go, I've had crazier.
十一去了颠倒世界 我们正常世界里真的需要一些魔法
And with Eleven in the Upside Down, we really need some magic up here.
正在想解决办法？
Working on a solution?
我想说 如果霍珀 有办法绕过这个 找到霍莉的话
I mean, if Hopper has a solution to get through this and to get to Holly,
他就应该跟我们分享！
he should… he should share it with us!
要我说 我们就无视那个老家伙
I just say we ignore the old man.
我们继续前进 找扇门之类的
We keep moving. Look for a door or something.
对 只是出于好奇
Yeah, and just curious.
你说的这扇门 也是像花生酱脆球一样柔软吗？
This door of yours, it's soft like a Peanut Butter Bopper?
拜尔斯 你要是有话想说 为什么不直说？
You got something to say, Byers, why don't you say it?
我只是想说 从现在开始 也许不应该由你做决定
I'm just saying maybe you shouldn't be making the calls from now on.
不止是他的决定 也是我的决定 因为失踪的是我妹妹
It was not just his call. It was mine because it's my sister.
And…
而且…
我同意史蒂夫的说法 好吧 我们不能就这么坐在这里
I agree with Steve. Okay, we can't just sit here.
我不知道有没有门 但这堵墙不可能没有尽头
I don't know about a door, but this wall can't go on forever.
肯定有办法绕过去的
There has to be a way around it.
没有办法
There isn't.
这堵墙是一个圆圈
This wall is a circle.
一个完全包围了颠倒世界的圆圈
A circle completely surrounding the Upside Down.
哦 是吗？你怎么知道的？
Oh yeah? How do you figure that?
因为我和你不一样 没有在代数1的课堂上呼呼大睡
Because unlike you, I didn't sleep through Algebra 1.
我的遥测追踪器 接收到了从墙上传来的奇怪频率
My telemetry tracker picked up a weird frequency coming from the wall,
我花了一点时间去思考 但我以前听到过这个声音
and it took me a bit to place, but I've heard it before.
或者说是我们听到过 记得我们在找霍珀的时候
Rather, we have. Remember when we were out looking for Hop,
你在欧文路旁边听到的声音吗？
and you heard that sound off of Irwin Road?
-记得 你说是干扰信号 -的确是
-Yeah. You said it was interference. -It was.
但这个干扰信号 并不是军事广播或电磁干扰
But this interference, it wasn't coming from a military broadcast or an EMI.
而是从这堵墙传来的 这一点很重要
It was coming from this wall, which is important,
因为这就给了我们三个已知地点
because that gives us three known locations.
于是我就把这几个点连了起来
So, I connected the dots,
测量了中点 画出垂直平分线…
measured the midpoints, drew the perpendicular bisectors--
好了！行吧 我们不是你的老师 你不需要给我们展示解题步骤
All right! Yeah, we're not your teachers. We don't need to see your work.
我们明白了 你觉得这是一个大圆圈
We get it. You think it's all a big circle.
我不是觉得 我是知道 我检查了三遍 我的计算是正确的
I don't think. I know. I triple checked, and my calculations are correct.
随便吧！我还是不明白 这怎么能让我们更接近找到霍莉
Whatever! I still don't see how this gets us closer to finding Holly.
因为重点不是圆圈 而是圆心
Because it's not about the circle. It's about the center.
DOE 能源部
The DOE. The Department of Energy.
-那是… -霍金斯实验室
-That's-- -Hawkins Lab.
这堵墙的中心有多大可能性
What are the chances that the center of this wall
刚好就是这一切开始的地方
happens to be in the place where all of this started,
颠倒世界被创造出来的地方？
where the Upside Down was created?
所以是实验室创造了这堵墙？
So, the lab created the wall?
不知道 但我觉得我们应该去查清楚
No idea. But I think we should find out.
不是吗？
Don't you?
音乐把我带去了新的记忆
The music, it led me to a new memory.
只是这段记忆有点不一样
Only, something was different about this memory.
我在场
I was there.
是亨利诅咒我的那天
It was the day that Henry cursed me.
是他对我的第一段记忆
It was his first memory of me.
我知道 就像这该死的地方 还不够烧脑一样 对吧？
I know, as if this goddamn place wasn't heady enough, right?
但还是有音乐在指引着我
But I still had the music to guide me.
于是我就跟了上去
So I followed it.
它又引导我经历了新的记忆
And it led me through new memories.
可怕的记忆
Terrible memories.
-放开我！ -跟随我一同赴死吧
-Let go! -Follow me into death.
感觉像是永远没有尽头
And it felt like they would never end.
但最终还是走到了尽头
But then eventually, they did.
是维克那杀死我的那晚
It was the night that Vecna killed me.
他把我抓来囚禁的那晚
The night he took me prisoner.
♪ Yeah, yeah, yo ♪
♪ Do you wanna know Know that it doesn't hurt me? ♪
我终于找到了
I'd finally found it.
♪ Do you wanna hear About the deal that I'm making? ♪
出去的路
The way out.
♪ It's you and me ♪
♪ And if I only could I'd make a deal with God ♪
♪ And I'd get him to swap… ♪
我是那么的接近
And I was so close.
近到我能感受到 他的手搭在我的手上
So close that I could feel his hand on mine.
我就像是真的在那里
And it was like I was there.
真的和他一起在医院里
Like I was with him in that hospital.
♪ Come on, Angel Come on, come on, darling ♪
♪ Let's exchange the experience ♪
不
No.
卢卡斯！
Lucas!
Lucas! Lucas! Lucas!
你好 麦克斯
Hello, Max.
我逃跑了
I ran.
我一直跑
And I kept running.
我永远不会忘记那天他脸上的表情
I'll never forget the look on his face that day.
他很害怕
He was scared.
不止是害怕 是恐惧
More than scared, he was terrified.
这个洞穴有些不一样…
There's something about this cave…
这段记忆
this memory.
他不会进来的
He won't come in.
在这里
In here,
我是安全的
I'm safe.
所以我把这里变成了我的避难所
So I turned it into my sanctuary.
我的家
My home.
我选了二号门
I took door two.
糟糕的二号门
Shitty door two.
认命
Accept your fate.
但这是
That was,
在你出现之前
until you showed up.
现在 三号门又有了可能
And now door three is back.
逃跑
Escape.
我有个计划 能让我们离开这里的计划
I have a plan, a plan to get us out of here.
这需要时间 我们目前没有这么多时间
And it's gonna take time, more time than we have now.
亨利很快就会回到他家里去
Henry will return to his house soon.
他回去时 不能让他知道你离开了
And when he does, he cannot know that you're gone.
你想让我回到那里去？
You want me to go back there?
回去找他？回到亨利身边？不…
Back to him? Back to Henry? No, I--
我知道 很可怕
I know. It's scary.
但如果你想离开这里 如果你想逃离坎马卓兹
But if you wanna get out of here, if you wanna escape Camazotz,
这是唯一的办法
this is the only way.
只有这一个办法
It's the only way.
告诉我该怎么做
Tell me what I need to do.
嘿 怎么…
Hey, wh--
-嘿 -你好
-Hey. -Hi.
你会不会还记得塔米·汤普森？
Do you, um, by any chance, remember Tammy Thompson?
记得 她不就是那个糟糕的歌手吗？
Yeah. Isn't she that terrible singer?
对
Yeah.
但九年级时
But in the ninth grade,
我觉得她的歌声 就像是该死的惠特妮·休斯顿
I thought that she sounded like Whitney goddamn Houston.
我第一次见到她时 我的天啊 时间都慢了下来
I mean, the first time I saw her, oh my God, like, time slowed down.
就像是某部烂片里的场景一样
It was like a scene from some lame-o movie.
她的头发随风飘扬 她的样子简直完美
You know, her hair blew in the wind, and she just looked perfect.
太完美了
So goddamn perfect.
就是在那个瞬间 我知道了她就是我想要的人
And, uh, it was right then and there that I knew she was the one.
和塔米在一起 我就终于可以 做我自己了 彻底做我自己
That with Tammy, I would finally be able to be myself, you know, all of myself.
因为我身上一直都有一部分 是让我有点害怕的 你知道吗？
Because there was always this part of me that kind of scared me, you know?
但我想着如果塔米爱我 爱我的全部
But I thought that if Tammy loved me, all of me,
我就不会再那么害怕了
you know, I wouldn't be so scared anymore.
然后他出现了 “秀发哥”史蒂夫·哈林顿
And then he showed up, Steve "The Hair" Harrington.
天啊
Oh God.
剩下的你大概都能猜得到
You probably can guess the rest.
塔米狠狠地迷上了他
Tammy fell for him hard.
我幻想中和她一起的生活 连同我的整个余生
And my entire fantasy life with her, along with the rest of my life,
几乎都在我眼前爆炸了
pretty much imploded before my eyes.
我的成绩一落千丈 我被禁足了
I mean, my grades plummeted. I got grounded.
我每个周末都不得不待在家里做家务
I had to stay home every weekend doing chores.
但有一天 在清理我父母车库里的蝙蝠屎的时候
But then one day, I was cleaning bat shit out of my parents' garage,
我找到了一卷8毫米胶片 你知道吗？
and I found this 8-millimeter film reel. You know?
只不过是我四年级时拍的傻傻的电影
And it was just from this silly movie that I made in fourth grade,
但我把胶片放进电影放映机里
but I got it up on the projector,
突然之间 看到小时候的我自己
and all of a sudden, I was looking at this little version of myself.
我差点认不出这个小小的我了
And that little me, I could hardly recognize her.
她是那么的无忧无虑
You know, she was so carefree
而且无所畏惧
and, like, fearless.
她由衷地爱着自己的每一面
She just loved every part of herself.
就在那时我突然意识到
And that's when it hit me.
重点其实从来都不是音盲塔米
It was never about Tone-deaf Tammy.
重点始终都在我自己身上
It was always just about me.
我始终在其他人身上寻找着答案 但…
I was looking for answers in somebody else, but…
所有答案都在我自己手上
I had all the answers.
我只需要别再这么害怕就行
I just needed to stop being so goddamn scared.
害怕真实的自己
Scared of… who I really was.
我这么做了之后
Once I did that, oh,
我觉得好自由啊
I felt so free.
就像是能飞起来一样 你知道吗？ 就像是我终于可以成为…
It's like I could fly, you know? Like, I could finally be…
摇滚罗宾了
Rockin' Robin.
对 摇滚罗宾
Yeah. Rockin' Robin.
嘿 二位！
Hey, guys!
慢慢走 不着急的 好吗？
Take your time, will ya?
你们终于找到迪克了吗？
Did you finally hit Dick?
-找到迪克了 -对
-Hit the Dick. -Yep.
希望不要太硬了
Let's just hope it's not too hard.
如果太硬
If it is,
我也会让它软下来
I'll soften it.
嘿！
Hey!
带我去见凯
Take me to Kay.
可恶！
Damn it! Damn it!
要是敢出声 你就死定了 听懂了就点个头
Make a sound, it'll be your last. Nod if you understand.
快走！走吧 我们走了！
Move! Move it! Come on, let's go!
快点！
Come on!
没用
It's not working.
-我们要怎么进去？ -我没有权限
-How do we get through? -I don't have clearance.
我没问你有没有权限 我问你我们怎么进去？
I didn't ask if you have clearance. I asked, how do we get through?
你们进不去的
You can't.
凯博士 你的老板 她有权限吗？
Dr. Kay, your boss, she got clearance?
我不知道
I don't know.
你不知道
You don't know.
多谢你的帮忙
Thanks for your help.
B计划
Plan B.
-停下！快停下！ -艾尔！
-Stop! Stop! -El!
-艾尔！ -停下！
-El! -Stop!
我们凿穿了
We're through.
哦 该死
Oh, shit.
该死
大家都闭上眼睛 把注意力放在你们的呼吸上
I want you to close your eyes and focus on your breathing.
吸气 呼气
Breathe in and out.
继续呼吸的同时
As you continue breathing,
想象你们自己在一片海滩上
I want you to picture yourself on a beach.
水是蓝色的 像蓝精灵一样蓝
The water is blue. Blue as a Smurf.
你们在听着它拍打沙滩的声音 就像一只狗从它的碗里吸食
You listen to it lap the sandy shore, like a dog slurping from his bowl.
这叫做形象化
It's called visualization.
我妈妈的地西泮吃光后 就会这么做
Mom does it when she's out of Valium.
（美国大兵 真正的美国英雄）
快去
Go.
（故障）
你好呀
Howdy.
感受屁股下面的沙子 感觉凉爽而柔软
Feel the sand under your butt. It feels cool and soft.
…一步一步来 这就对了
…time. There you go.
好样的 干得好 很好
Good job, good job. All right.
嘿 亲爱的 你叫什么名字？
Hey, sweetie. Um, what's your name?
黛比
Debbie.
你是为啥先生工作的吗？
Do you work for Mr. Whatsit?
啥先生
Mr. Whatsit.
对 当然 我是他的一个精灵
Oh. Um, yes. Of course. I'm one of his elves.
就是那种魔法精灵
You know, like a… a magic elf.
就在这里 再多走几步
Right here. A couple more steps.
好的 没错 很好
All right. Yes, okay.
好了 很好 一步一步来
All right. Great job. Step by step.
该死
Shit.
十一
Eleven.
我找你已经找了很久了
I have been looking for you for a very long time.
我的名字是…
My name is--
凯博士
Dr. Kay.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
我知道你抓了谁
I know who you've taken.
我也知道…
And I also know…
你和你的手下们…
that you and your men…
都必死无疑
are going to die.
搞什么？
What the hell?
我劝你最好不要挣扎
It's best not to struggle.
感知到的威胁越大 它的反应就会越激烈
The greater the perceived threat, the more aggressive its response.
罗宾小姐 其他人呢？
Miss Robin, what about the others?
叫我罗宾就行了 别担心 他们随后就到
Uh, just Robin. And don't worry. They're right behind us.
出事了 对吧？
-Something's wrong, isn't it? -No. No, siree.
不 没有 当然没有！ 一切顺利 完全在按计划进行
Everything is going exactly according to plan.
-气闸…用你的外套包起来 -我能搞定
-Airlock-- Wrap it with your jacket. -I got it.
等一下 稍等
Hold it. Hold it. Hold it.
来 试试看…
Here. Try it--
嘿 对不起 这里的管道出了点问题
Hey. Sorry. Bit of a plumbing problem here.
你会不会是在找啥先生？
Are you by chance looking for Mr. Whatsit?
-就在那边 -从那里进去就行
-Right through there. -Right there.
有一点微风从海边吹来
There's a little breeze in the air telling you a secret.
抬头仰望天空 想要寻找云朵 但你们只能…
You look up at the sky, searching for clouds, but all you--
啥先生？
Mr. Whatsit?
该死！
Shit!
警官！
Officer! Officer!
哇 嘿 冷静点
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey, calm down.
-怎么了？ -这下坏了
-What's going on? -Shitballs.
好样的 朋友
Good job, man.
-卢卡斯！我们被发现了！ -不 不好！
-Lucas! We've been spotted! -No, no!
把他们都带出去 快去
Get 'em out of here. Go.
-那其他人呢？ -快走吧！快走！
-What about the others? -Just go! Go, go, go!
可恶！好了 大家跟我来吧
Damn it! Okay, come on, guys.
快走！
Move! Move! Move! Move! Move! Move! Move! Move! Move!
喂 站住！
Hey, stop right there!
阿希莉·克莱恩是个告密贼！
Ashley Klein is a snitch!
嘿！
Hey!
开门！快把门打开！
Open the door! Open the goddamn door!
所以你就是原因
So you're the reason.
这么难追踪到她的原因
The reason she's been so hard to track.
我的眼中钉
The thorn in my side.
费了好大劲把她藏起来 你却把她带来了这里？
And after all that effort to hide her, you bring her here, of all places?
为什么？
Why?
为什么要为另一个人 让她冒上生命危险？
Why risk her life for the other?
你知道什么我不知道的事？
What do you know that I don't?
它其实还留余力了 如果你能相信的话
It's actually holding back, if you can believe it.
你感受到的这个热度…
That heat you feel…
削弱了它
weakens it.
但在寒冷中 它会大展拳脚
But in the cold, it thrives.
我可以阻止它
I can stop it.
但你得老实交代
But you're gonna have to start talking.
去死吧
Go to hell.
以你目前的状态 恐怕是行不通的
In your current state, I'm afraid that won't work.
你的头脑不太敏锐 是吧？
Not the sharpest, are we?
你太迟了 援军已经在路上了
You're too late. Cavalry's on its way.
没关系
That's all right.
我会速战速决
I'll be quick.
杂货配送
Grocery delivery.
其他人呢？
Where's everyone else?
随后就到
Coming.
来吧 亲爱的 快下来吧 快来
Come on, sweetie. Come on down. Come on.
你现在就给我下来 否则怪物就会把你吃掉
You get down here right now, or a monster's gonna eat you.
把门打开！
Open the door!
该死！
You little shit!
让开！
Get out of the way!
你们总算来了！
About goddamn time!
我抓住你了 非常好 很好
I got you. That's good. Good, good.
你们好啊 你们这是要去哪儿？
Hey there. Where do you think you're going?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
嘿 你得走了 你得离开 来吧
Hey, you gotta go. You gotta go. Come on.
你要到树林里去
We're gonna get to the woods.
那些氪石在那里影响不到你
The kryptonite shit can't get you there.
霍珀 不可以 我们不能离开 我们是来找亨利的
Hop, we can't. We can't leave. We came for Henry.
嘿 拿着这个指南针 你跟着它往东北方向走
Hey. You take this compass. You're gonna follow it northeast.
它会把你带去墓地 你会在那里找到南茜和其他人
That'll take you to the graveyard. You're gonna find Nancy and the others.
哇 嘿
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey, hey, hey. Hey.
那是什么？
What is that?
这只是以防万一 好吗？
It's just a failsafe, okay?
-以防万一 -不
-It's a failsafe. -No.
万一发生不测 我得拉着他一起死
I gotta make sure he goes down with me.
-不 不要 霍珀 -这是唯一的办法 只有这一个办法
-No. No, Hop. -It's the only way. It's the only way.
我不会冒上失去你的风险
I'm not gonna risk losing you.
我不会冒险的
I will not risk it.
-霍珀 不要 -听着 我想让你知道一件事
-Hopper. No. -Listen, I want you to know something.
从现在开始
From here on out,
我想要你知道我有多为你骄傲
I want you to know how proud I am of you.
我真为你骄傲 我为你所克服的一切深感骄傲
I am so proud of you. I am so proud of what you've overcome.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm proud of who you are.
不
No.
不 不要 霍珀！
No. No, Hop. Hopper!
-我爱你 简 -霍珀！不！霍珀！
-I love you, Jane. -Hopper! No! Hopper!
霍珀！
Hop!
Hopper!
霍珀！
Hop!
Hopper!
霍珀！
Hopper! Hopper!
Hopper!
血氧在下跌
Pulse ox is falling.
心脏停止跳动了！
Flatlining!
好了 孩子们 来吧 在后面找个位子坐下
All right, kids. Come on. Find a seat in the back.
嗨
Hi.
好了
All right.
好了 我们好好玩玩吧 肯定会很好玩的 对吧？
Okay, let's have some fun, huh? This is gonna be great, huh?
好了 我们系好安全带 好吗？
Okay. Let's get our seat belts on, hmm?
安全第一 来吧 别浪费时间
Safety first. Come on. Time's a-wastin'.
很舒服吧？
Pretty comfy, huh?
算不上
Not really.
抱歉了
Oh, sorry.
罗宾、卢卡斯 能听到吗？完毕
Robin, Lucas, do you copy? Over.
听到了 我是罗宾
Copy. It's Robin.
卢卡斯 我听到了
Lucas. I copy.
军管区这里出了些问题
We've got a problem here at the MAC.
什么问题？
What kind of problem?
放开我 你个混蛋！
Let go of me, you asshole!
你想跟我解释一下 到底发生了什么事吗？
You want to explain to me what in God's name is going on here?
快放开我
Get the hell off me.
-有五个孩子失踪了 长官 -你们弄丢了五个孩子？
-We've got five missing kids, sir. -You've lost five kids?
-这怎么可能？ -这个女人…
-How is that possible? -This woman--
乔伊斯·拜尔斯
Joyce Byers.
她闯进了军营
She broke into the barracks.
用某种隧道帮助他们逃跑了
She's been helping them escape through some kind of tunnel.
对不起 你能重复一遍吗？
I'm sorry. Can you repeat that?
听着 这些孩子不安全 好吗？他们有生命危险
Listen. These kids, they are not safe, okay? They are in danger.
那你觉得 他们为什么会来这里 女士？
And why exactly do you think they're here, ma'am? Hmm?
他们在我们的保护之下
They're under our protection.
请容我插一句 警官 我已经看到了将要发生的事
If I may interject, officer. I've seen what's coming.
没有不尊重你的意思 但你和你的手下们屁都保护不了！
And no disrespect meant, but you and your men can't protect shit!
-二等兵！ -嘿！
-Private! -Hey! Hey!
-放开他！ -嘿 二等兵！
-Get off him! -Hey, Private!
你到底什么毛病 二等兵？不许碰他
What the hell is wrong with you, Private? Keep your hands off him.
军队就是做这种事吗？就会打小孩？
Is that all the military does? Hit kids?
-威尔！ -威尔！
-Will! -Will! Will! Will!
你没事吧？宝贝 你没事吧？
Are you okay? Baby, are you okay?
他们来了
They're here.
干掉距离最近的威胁 发现即开火！
Take the nearest threat! Engage on sight!
我们都会死的！
We're all gonna die! We're all gonna die!
各位！站到我身后去！
Guys! Guys! Guys! Get behind me! Get behind me!
退后！
Get back!
床底下！
Under the beds! Under the beds!
Under the beds! Under the beds! Under the beds! Under the beds!
站在我身后
Stay behind me. Stay behind me.
行动！
Move! Move! Move!
威尔！
Will!
我们受到攻击 我再说一遍 我们受到攻击了
We are under attack. I repeat, we are under attack.
我们得走了！
We gotta go. We gotta go!
其他孩子怎么办？该死！
What about the other kids? Shit!
快走！
Go, go, go, go, go!
快点 走不走？
Come on, shall we?
走了！
We shall!
我们要逃出去 好吗？ 盯着我！靠近一点！
We're getting out of here, all right? Eyes on me! Stay close!
好的 好
Okay, okay.
威尔 拜托 来吧！
Will, come on. Come on!
-来吧 -等等我 拜托！等一等！
-Come on. -Wait for me, please! Wait!
我还没准备好去死！
I'm not ready to die!
-等一等！ -靠近一点！
-Wait up! -Stay close!
德瑞克！快点 我们走！
Derek! Hurry up, let's go!
-大家都没事吧？你们没事吧？ -对
-Is everybody okay? Are you guys okay? -Yeah.
好了 那家无线电小屋 如果我们速度够快 应该能跑到
Okay. The Radio Shack. If we move quick enough, I think we can make it.
进入隧道 逃离这里
Get into the tunnels and get out of here.
-好 -好吗？
-Okay. -Okay?
盯着我 记得吗？好的
Eyes on me. Remember?
停下！
Stop, stop, stop, stop!
好 快走！
All right, go!
接招吧！
Get some!
快走！天啊
Go, go, go! Oh my God.
天啊！
Oh my God!
坚持住 宝贝！坚持住！
Just hold on, baby! Hold on!
-刚刚到底发生了什么？ -我不知道 但我很喜欢
-What the hell just happened? -I have no idea, but I love it!
姐姐
Sister.
妹妹
开火！
Unload!
小心！
Watch out!
穆雷！
Murray!
狗娘养的！
Son of a bitch!
啊 该死！
Oh, shit, shit, shit!
哇！
Whoa!
孩子们！
The kids!
抓牢了！
Hold on!
快走！大家快走！
Move, move, move! Let's go, guys!
大家后退！后退！
Back up, guys! Back up!
离他远点！你给我离远点！
Stay away from him! You stay away!
你能看到他们吗？
Can you see them…
威廉？
William?
你能看到那些孩子们吗？
Can you see the children?
你知道为什么吗？
Do you know why?
我为什么选了他们来重塑世界？
Why I chose them to reshape the world?
因为他们很软弱
It's because they are weak.
在身体和精神上都很软弱
Weak in body and mind.
求求你了！
Please!
很容易崩溃
Easily broken.
很容易重塑
Easily reshaped.
很容易控制
Controlled.
完美的载体
The perfect vessels.
而你…
And you…
威尔
Will.
你是第一个
You were the first.
你那么轻易就崩溃了
And you broke so easily.
你向我展示了什么是可能的
You showed me what was possible,
什么是我能够完成的
what I could achieve.
事实证明 有些头脑
Some minds, it turns out,
根本就不属于这个世界
simply do not belong in this world.
而是属于我的世界
They belong in mine.
我始终在其他人身上寻找着答案 但…
I was looking for the answers in somebody else, but…
所有答案都在我自己手上
I had all the answers.
你想当朋友吗？
Do you wanna be friends?
我只…
I just…
需要别再这么该死的害怕了
needed to stop being so goddamn scared.
害怕真实的自己
Scared of who I really was.
哇！好棒啊！
Wow! It's so good!
（欢迎所有朋友）
（拜尔斯城堡）
我这么做了之后
And once I did that,
我觉得好自由啊
I was so free.
就像是能飞起来一样
It's like I could fly.